<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="app_name">Wire Reference</string>
<string name="about">About:</string>
<string name="about_btn">About</string>
<string name="about_title"></string>
<string name="about_close"></string>
<string name="description">Utility to help wire up Data and Voice cables.\n</string>
<string name="cat5about">The specification for Category 5 cable was defined in ANSI/TIA/EIA-568-A, with clarification in TSB-95. These documents specified performance characteristics and test requirements for frequencies of up to 100 MHz. Cable types, connector types and cabling topologies are defined by TIA/EIA-568-B. The cable is terminated in either the T568A scheme or the T568B scheme. The two schemes work equally well and may be mixed in an installation so long as the same scheme is used on both ends of each cable. Nearly always, 8P8C modular connectors, often referred to as RJ45, are used for connecting category 5 cable. The USOC/RJ-61 standard is used in multi-line telephone connections.\n\n Each of the four pairs in a Cat 5 cable has differing precise number of twists per metre to minimize crosstalk between the pairs. Although cable assemblies containing 4 pairs are common, Category 5 is not limited to 4 pairs. Backbone applications involve using up to 100 pairs. This use of balanced lines helps preserve a high signal-to-noise ratio despite interference from both external sources and crosstalk from other pairs. Category 5 cabling is most commonly used for faster Ethernet networks, such as 100BASE-TX and 1000BASE-T.\n\n The cable is available in both stranded and solid conductor forms. The stranded form is more flexible and withstands more bending without breaking and is suited for reliable connections with insulation piercing connectors, but makes unreliable connections in insulation-displacement connectors (IDCs). The solid form is less expensive and makes reliable connections into insulation displacement connectors, but makes unreliable connections in insulation piercing connectors. Taking these things into account, building wiring (for example, the wiring inside the wall that connects a wall socket to a central patch panel) is solid core, while patch cables (for example, the movable cable that plugs into the wall socket on one end and a computer on the other) are stranded. Outer insulation is typically PVC or LSOH. The specific category of cable in use can be identified by the printing on the side of the cable.</string>
<string name="cat5aradius">Most Category 5 cables can be bent at any radius exceeding approximately four times the diameter of the cable.\n\n According to the ANSI/TIA/EIA standard for category 5e copper cable (TIA/EIA 568-5-A), the maximum length for a cable segment is 100 meters (328 feet). If longer runs are required, the use of active hardware such as a repeater, or a switch, is necessary. The specifications for 10BASE-T networking specify a 100 metre length between active devices. This allows for 90 metres of fixed cabling, two connectors and two patch leads of 5 metres, one at each end.</string>
<string name="cat5aconductors">10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX Ethernet connections require two cable pairs. \n\n 1000BASE-T Ethernet connections require four cable pairs.</string>
<string name="cat5A">TIA/EIA&#8211;568&#8211;A.1&#8211;2001 Cat 5 A</string>
<string name="cat5B">TIA/EIA&#8211;568&#8211;B.1&#8211;2001 Cat 5 B</string>
<string name="cat5xover">E10BASE-T or 100BASE-TX Crossover</string>
<string name="cat5xoverdescribe">An Ethernet crossover cable is a type of Ethernet cable used to connect computing devices together directly. Normal straight through or patch cables were used to connect from a host network interface controller (a computer or similar device) to a network switch, hub or router. A cable with connections that "cross over" was used to connect two devices of the same type: two hosts or two switches to each other. Owing to the inclusion of Auto-MDIX capability, modern implementations of the Ethernet over twisted pair standards usually no longer require the use of crossover cables.</string>
<string name="cat5xoveroverview">The 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX Ethernet standards use one wire pair for transmission in each direction. By convention, one wire of the pair is designated "+" and the other "-". Following traditional telephone terminology, the + signal from each pair connects to the tip conductor, and the - signal is connected to the ring conductor. This requires that the transmit pair of each device be connected to the receive pair of the device on the other end. When a terminal device is connected to a switch or hub, this crossover is done internally in the switch or hub. A standard straight through cable is used for this purpose where each pin of the connector on one end is connected to the corresponding pin on the other connector. \n\nOne network interface controller may be connected directly to another without the use of a switch or hub, but in that case the crossover must be done externally in the cable or modular crossover adapter in a manner similar to how the null modem was used to directly connect two teleprinters. Since 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX use pairs 2 and 3, these two pairs must be swapped in the cable. This is a crossover cable. A crossover cable was also used to connect two hubs or two switches on their upstream ports . \n\nBecause the only difference between the T568A and T568B pin/pair assignments are that pairs 2 and 3 are swapped, a crossover cable may be envisioned as a cable with one modular connector following T568A and the other T568B (see Jack crossover wiring). Such a cable will work for 10BASE-T or 100BASE-TX. Gigabit Ethernet (and an early Fast Ethernet variant, 100BASE-T4) use all four pairs and also requires the other two pairs (1 and 4) to be swapped. This meant common crossover cables available in the retail market were usually not compatible with the Gigabit Ethernet convention, but newer crossover cables could be made that worked for all speeds. The polarity of each pair is not swapped, but the pairs crossed as a unit: the two wires within each pair are not crossed.</string>
<string name="cat5xoverpinouts">In practice, it does not matter if non-crossover Ethernet cables are wired as T568A or T568B, just so long as both ends follow the same wiring format. Typical commercially available "pre-wired" cables can follow either format depending the manufacturer. What this means is that one manufacturer\'s cables are wired one way and another\'s the other way, yet both are correct and will work. In either case, T568A or T568B, a normal (un-crossed) cable will have both ends wired according to the layout in the Connection 1 column. \n\nAlthough the Gigabit crossover is defined in the Gigabit Ethernet standard, in practice all Gigabit PHYs feature an auto-MDIX capability and are designed for compatibility with the existing 100BASE-TX crossovers. The IEEE-specified Gigabit crossover is generally seen as unnecessary. \n\nCertain equipment or installations, including those in which phone and or power are mixed with data in the same cable, may require that the "non-data" pairs 1 and 4 (pins 4, 5, 7 and 8) remain un-crossed.</string>
<string name="cat5xoverga">Gigabit T568A crossover</string>
<string name="cat5xovergadescribe">An Ethernet crossover cable is a type of Ethernet cable used to connect computing devices together directly. Normal straight through or patch cables were used to connect from a host network interface controller (a computer or similar device) to a network switch, hub or router. A cable with connections that "cross over" was used to connect two devices of the same type: two hosts or two switches to each other. Owing to the inclusion of Auto-MDIX capability, modern implementations of the Ethernet over twisted pair standards usually no longer require the use of crossover cables.</string>
<string name="cat5xovergaoverview">The 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX Ethernet standards use one wire pair for transmission in each direction. By convention, one wire of the pair is designated "+" and the other "-". Following traditional telephone terminology, the + signal from each pair connects to the tip conductor, and the - signal is connected to the ring conductor. This requires that the transmit pair of each device be connected to the receive pair of the device on the other end. When a terminal device is connected to a switch or hub, this crossover is done internally in the switch or hub. A standard straight through cable is used for this purpose where each pin of the connector on one end is connected to the corresponding pin on the other connector. \n\nOne network interface controller may be connected directly to another without the use of a switch or hub, but in that case the crossover must be done externally in the cable or modular crossover adapter in a manner similar to how the null modem was used to directly connect two teleprinters. Since 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX use pairs 2 and 3, these two pairs must be swapped in the cable. This is a crossover cable. A crossover cable was also used to connect two hubs or two switches on their upstream ports . \n\nBecause the only difference between the T568A and T568B pin/pair assignments are that pairs 2 and 3 are swapped, a crossover cable may be envisioned as a cable with one modular connector following T568A and the other T568B (see Jack crossover wiring). Such a cable will work for 10BASE-T or 100BASE-TX. Gigabit Ethernet (and an early Fast Ethernet variant, 100BASE-T4) use all four pairs and also requires the other two pairs (1 and 4) to be swapped. This meant common crossover cables available in the retail market were usually not compatible with the Gigabit Ethernet convention, but newer crossover cables could be made that worked for all speeds. The polarity of each pair is not swapped, but the pairs crossed as a unit: the two wires within each pair are not crossed.</string>
<string name="cat5xovergapinouts">In practice, it does not matter if non-crossover Ethernet cables are wired as T568A or T568B, just so long as both ends follow the same wiring format. Typical commercially available "pre-wired" cables can follow either format depending the manufacturer. What this means is that one manufacturer\'s cables are wired one way and another\'s the other way, yet both are correct and will work. In either case, T568A or T568B, a normal (un-crossed) cable will have both ends wired according to the layout in the Connection 1 column. \n\nAlthough the Gigabit crossover is defined in the Gigabit Ethernet standard, in practice all Gigabit PHYs feature an auto-MDIX capability and are designed for compatibility with the existing 100BASE-TX crossovers. The IEEE-specified Gigabit crossover is generally seen as unnecessary. \n\nCertain equipment or installations, including those in which phone and or power are mixed with data in the same cable, may require that the "non-data" pairs 1 and 4 (pins 4, 5, 7 and 8) remain un-crossed.</string>
<string name="cat5xovergb">Gigabit T568B crossover</string>
<string name="cat5xovergbdescribe">An Ethernet crossover cable is a type of Ethernet cable used to connect computing devices together directly. Normal straight through or patch cables were used to connect from a host network interface controller (a computer or similar device) to a network switch, hub or router. A cable with connections that "cross over" was used to connect two devices of the same type: two hosts or two switches to each other. Owing to the inclusion of Auto-MDIX capability, modern implementations of the Ethernet over twisted pair standards usually no longer require the use of crossover cables.</string>
<string name="cat5xovergboverview">The 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX Ethernet standards use one wire pair for transmission in each direction. By convention, one wire of the pair is designated "+" and the other "-". Following traditional telephone terminology, the + signal from each pair connects to the tip conductor, and the - signal is connected to the ring conductor. This requires that the transmit pair of each device be connected to the receive pair of the device on the other end. When a terminal device is connected to a switch or hub, this crossover is done internally in the switch or hub. A standard straight through cable is used for this purpose where each pin of the connector on one end is connected to the corresponding pin on the other connector. \n\nOne network interface controller may be connected directly to another without the use of a switch or hub, but in that case the crossover must be done externally in the cable or modular crossover adapter in a manner similar to how the null modem was used to directly connect two teleprinters. Since 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX use pairs 2 and 3, these two pairs must be swapped in the cable. This is a crossover cable. A crossover cable was also used to connect two hubs or two switches on their upstream ports . \n\nBecause the only difference between the T568A and T568B pin/pair assignments are that pairs 2 and 3 are swapped, a crossover cable may be envisioned as a cable with one modular connector following T568A and the other T568B (see Jack crossover wiring). Such a cable will work for 10BASE-T or 100BASE-TX. Gigabit Ethernet (and an early Fast Ethernet variant, 100BASE-T4) use all four pairs and also requires the other two pairs (1 and 4) to be swapped. This meant common crossover cables available in the retail market were usually not compatible with the Gigabit Ethernet convention, but newer crossover cables could be made that worked for all speeds. The polarity of each pair is not swapped, but the pairs crossed as a unit: the two wires within each pair are not crossed.</string>
<string name="cat5xovergbpinouts">In practice, it does not matter if non-crossover Ethernet cables are wired as T568A or T568B, just so long as both ends follow the same wiring format. Typical commercially available "pre-wired" cables can follow either format depending the manufacturer. What this means is that one manufacturer\'s cables are wired one way and another\'s the other way, yet both are correct and will work. In either case, T568A or T568B, a normal (un-crossed) cable will have both ends wired according to the layout in the Connection 1 column. \n\nAlthough the Gigabit crossover is defined in the Gigabit Ethernet standard, in practice all Gigabit PHYs feature an auto-MDIX capability and are designed for compatibility with the existing 100BASE-TX crossovers. The IEEE-specified Gigabit crossover is generally seen as unnecessary. \n\nCertain equipment or installations, including those in which phone and or power are mixed with data in the same cable, may require that the "non-data" pairs 1 and 4 (pins 4, 5, 7 and 8) remain un-crossed.</string>
<string name="poeabout">Power over Ethernet or PoE technology describes a system to pass electrical power safely, along with data, on Ethernet cabling. The IEEE standard for PoE requires Category 5 cable or higher for high power levels, but can operate with category 3 cable for low power levels. Power is supplied in common mode over two or more of the differential pairs of wires found in the Ethernet cables and comes from a power supply within a PoE-enabled networking device such as an Ethernet switch or can be injected into a cable run with a midspan power supply. \n\nThe original IEEE 802.3af-2003 PoE standard provides up to 15.4 W of DC power (minimum 44 V DC and 350 mA) to each device. Only 12.95 W is assured to be available at the powered device as some power is dissipated in the cable. \n\nThe updated IEEE 802.3at-2009 PoE standard also known as PoE+ or PoE plus, provides up to 25.5 W of power. The 2009 standard prohibits a powered device from using all four pairs for power. Some vendors have announced products that claim to be compatible with the 802.3at standard and offer up to 51 W of power over a single cable by utilizing all four pairs in the Category 5 cable. \n\nNumerous non-standard schemes had been used prior to PoE standardization to provide power over Ethernet cabling. Some are still in active use.</string>
<string name="poecompare">PoE provides both data and power connections in one cable, so equipment doesn\'t need a separate cable for each need. For equipment that does not already have a power or data connection, PoE can be attractive when the power demand is modest. For example, PoE is useful for IP telephones, wireless LAN access points, cameras with pan tilt and zoom (PTZ), and remote Ethernet switches. PoE can provide long cable runs (e.g., 100 meters (330 ft)) and can deliver 12 W galvanically isolated power. PoE plus can provide even more power. \n\nThere are competing technologies. The Universal Serial Bus (USB) provides both data and power, but it is designed for short cables (5 meters (16 ft) maximum length) and provides less than 2.5 W of non-isolated power. It is less expensive than PoE, and works well for low power peripherals such as a computer mouse, a headset/microphone, or a serial port. Some peripherals, such as speakers, scanners, and printers, need more power than USB can provide. Firewire is similar to USB, but it can provide substantially more power. On the other hand, USB peripherals can operate at very low power levels; maintaining an Ethernet connection consumes a lot of power. \n\nIf a device already has power available but no data connection, then PoE may not be attractive. A wireless data connection such as IEEE 802.11 may be more economical than running a data cable for the device. Alternatively, there are power line communication technologies that can use power cables for transmitting data. Using some power line modems may be more economical than running a cable. \n\nIf data rate and power requirements are both low, then other approaches may be viable. Cellular phones, for example, use batteries for power and wireless data connections. Remote weather sensors have very low data rates, so batteries (possibly supplemented with solar power) and custom wireless data connections are used. Replacing batteries is a nuisance, but if the batteries last six months or a year, the practice may be tolerable. \n\nDepending on the application, PoE can have advantages over other technologies: \n\nInexpensive cabling \n\nModest power \n\nFast data rate \n\nPeer-to-peer network access. Once a device is connected to the network, it is accessible to many users.</string>
<string name="poeuses">Some types of devices with PoE include: \n\nIP Security Cameras \n\nNetwork routers \n\nA mini network switch installed in distant rooms, to support a small cluster of ports from one uplink cable. (These ports on the mini-switch do not themselves provide PoE.) (In most modern VoIP phones a two-port switch is embedded to which a local workstation can be installed using a different VLAN from the voice-VLAN used by the phone itself) \n\nNetwork webcams\n\nNetwork Intercom / Paging / Public address systems and hallway speaker amplifiers \n\nVoIP phones \n\nWall clocks in rooms and hallways, with time set using Network Time Protocol \n\nWireless access points \n\nOutdoor roof mounted radios with integrated antennas, 802.11 or 802.16 based wireless CPEs (customer premises equipment) used by wireless ISPs. \n\nIndustrial devices (sensors, controllers, meters etc.) \n\nAccess control and Help-points (intercoms, entry cards, keyless entry, etc.) \n\nLighting controllers \n\nRemote Point of Sale (POS) kiosks \n\nPhysical Security devices and controllers</string>
<string name="poestanimplem">Standards-based power over Ethernet is implemented following the specifications in IEEE 802.3af-2003 (which was later incorporated as clause 33 into IEEE 802.3-2005) or the 2009 update, IEEE 802.3at. A phantom power technique is used to allow the powered pairs to also carry data. This permits its use not only with 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX, which use only two of the four pairs in the cable, but also with 1000BASE-T (gigabit Ethernet), which uses all four pairs for data transmission. This is possible because all versions of Ethernet over twisted pair cable specify differential data transmission over each pair with transformer coupling; the DC supply and load connections can be made to the transformer center-taps at each end. Each pair thus operates in common mode as one side of the DC supply, so two pairs are required to complete the circuit. The polarity of the DC supply may be inverted by crossover cables; the powered device must operate with either pair: spare pairs 4–5 and 7–8 or data pairs 1–2 and 3–6. Polarity is required on data pairs, and ambiguously implemented for spare pairs, with the use of a diode bridge.</string>
<string name="poestanimdescribe">POE Standard Implementation Description</string>
<string name="poestanimchart">POE Standard Implementation Chart</string>
<string name="poeplevel">POEplevel</string>
<string name="poepowerlevels">POE Power Levels</string>
<string name="poepowerdevicesdescribeb">Powering Devices Description</string>
<string name="poepowerdevicesdescribe">Two modes, A and B, are available. Mode A delivers power on the data pairs of 100BASE-TX or 10BASE-T. Mode B delivers power on the spare pairs. PoE can also be used on 1000BASE-T Ethernet in which case, there are no spare pairs and all power is delivered using the phantom technique. \n\nMode A has two alternate configurations (MDI and MDI-X), using the same pairs but with different polarities. In mode A, pins 1 and 2 (pair #2 in T568B wiring) form one side of the 48 V DC, and pins 3 and 6 (pair #3 in T568B) form the other side. These are the same two pairs used for data transmission in 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX, allowing the provision of both power and data over only two pairs in such networks. The free polarity allows PoE to accommodate for crossover cables, patch cables and auto-MDIX. \n\nIn mode B, pins 4–5 (pair #1 in both T568A and T568B) form one side of the DC supply and pins 7–8 (pair #4 in both T568A and T568B) provide the return; these are the "spare" pairs in 10BASE-T and 100BASE-TX. Mode B, therefore, requires a 4-pair cable. \n\nThe PSE, not the powered device (PD), decides whether power mode A or B shall be used. PDs that implement only Mode A or Mode B are disallowed by the standard. \n\nThe PSE can implement mode A or B or both. A PD indicates that it is standards-compliant by placing a 25 kΩ resistor between the powered pairs. If the PSE detects a resistance that is too high or too low (including a short circuit), no power is applied. This protects devices that do not support PoE. An optional "power class" feature allows the PD to indicate its power requirements by changing the sense resistance at higher voltages. To stay powered, the PD must continuously use 5–10 mA for at least 60 ms with no more than 400 ms since last use or else it will be unpowered by the PSE. \n\nThere are two types of PSEs: endspans and midspans. Endspans are Ethernet switches that include the power over Ethernet transmission circuitry. Endspans are commonly called PoE switches. Midspans are power injectors that stand between a regular Ethernet switch and the powered device, injecting power without affecting the data. \n\nEndspans are normally used on new installations or when the switch has to be replaced for other reasons (such as moving from 10/100 Mbit/s to 1 Gbit/s or adding security protocols), which makes it convenient to add the PoE capability. Midspans are used when there is no desire to replace and configure a new Ethernet switch, and only PoE needs to be added to the network.</string>
<string name="poepowerdeviceschart">Power Levels Available</string>
<string name="poepowerdeviceschart2">Stages of powering up a PoE link</string>
<string name="poe">POE</string>
<string name="rj11">RJ11</string>
<string name="rj14">RJ14</string>
<string name="rj14wiring">RJ14 Wiring</string>
<string name="t568awiring">T568A Wiring</string>
<string name="pin">Pin</string>
<string name="pair">Pair</string>
<string name="wire">Wire</string>
<string name="color">Color</string>

<style name="ButtonText">
    <item name="android:layout_width">fill_parent</item>
    <item name="android:layout_height">wrap_content</item>
    <item name="android:textColor">#ffffff</item>
    <item name="android:gravity">center</item>
    <item name="android:layout_margin">3dp</item>
    <item name="android:textSize">15dp</item>
    <item name="android:textStyle">bold</item>
    <item name="android:shadowColor">#000000</item>
    <item name="android:shadowDx">1</item>
    <item name="android:shadowDy">1</item>
    <item name="android:shadowRadius">2</item>
</style>
    <string name="signal">Signal</string>
</resources>



